Matthew Brune

Highly adaptable and versatile front-end engineer with a passion for creating seamless user interfaces (UI) across a variety of business needs. Experienced with User Experience/UI design, SEO, ad operations, accessibility, and analytics. Proven manager and scrum runner.

1365 Memorial Drive SE
Unit 2
Atlanta, GA, 30317
(404) 234-1589
matthewrbrune@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/matthew-brune/

EXPERIENCE

Freelance (Multiple Clients), Atlanta — UI/UX Engineer

July 2024 - Present

- Redesigned and implemented UI changes in Squarespace for a non-profit Arts Council to optimize their UX with a focus on accessibility.
- Collaborated with clients on branding changes to better capture the client's personality to stand out in competitive industries such as film.

Sharecare, Atlanta — Senior Software Engineer

March 2020 - June 2024

- Utilized Node, Express JS, NextJS, and React to develop and maintain highly customized, API-dependent microservices.
- Engineered, developed and maintained state and stateless React global components while meeting internal and third-party requirements.
- Led numerous features through the development life cycle such as building requirements, project planning, delegation and code reviewing, and ultimately documentation and production release via Kubernetes/Docker.
- Identified accessibility deficiencies across our many microservices and helped bring our scores up 50-60% through multiple approaches from DOM structure to more basic aspects of ADA compliance such as aria-* attributes.

Sharecare, Atlanta — Software Engineer

March 2018 - March 2020

- Created several NextJS based microservices to support urgent initiatives such
 as the outbreak of COVID-19 in which we provided a service supplying
 content, guidance and vital information, which garnered the accolades of
 multiple Digital Health Awards in 2020.
- Created RESTful API resources to help facilitate sitewide branding synergy and other front-end resources where we needed to support integrations across multiple microservices and even external companies using shared components.
- Took initiative to co-design a content recommendation API and corresponding React components with their own design system to help build up our internal linking strategies and ultimately improved our bounce rate and SEO rankings.

Sharecare, Atlanta — Junior UI Engineer

MAY 2014 - March 2018

- Built and customized multiple BEM designed CSS strategies for a series of global components in an effort to reduce stylesheet bloat and increase developer clarity and productivity.
- Maintained and converted site infrastructure from monolithic Java/JSTL-based application to single Node and React based microservices including rewriting core dependencies to the latest ECMAScript standards.

SKILLS

HTML, JS, CSS, SCSS, React, NextJS, Express, Node, VueJs, Handlebars/Jade, Tailwind and some Typescript

Amazon S3 Cloud API Usage, Google Lighthouse, Jenkins, Docker, Github Actions, Kubernetes, DigitalOcean, Loggly, Grafana

MS Suite, JIRA, Figma, Zeplin, Adobe Suite, Canva

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology

BS Computational Media Aug 2009 - May 2013

High Honors and Co-operative Program Designation

EXTRACURRICULARS

Kingfect - Real Estate SPA

Created a marketing website and proof of concept SPA in VueJS.

Discord Bots - Realtime Contest Feedback

Created a Discord bot using their API to return the top X amount of participants so they can see live rankings via commands.